Finding Aid for Humane Society of Huron Valley records, 1896-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Humane Society of Huron Valley records 1896-1970
Humane Society of Huron Valley.
1 linear foot
85213 Bj 2
Board minutes, annual reports; photographs; also files relating to the construction and expansion of the shelter, to problems of dog control, and concerning local animal control ordinances.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group came from the organization (donor no. 6320 ) in 1979; a few items had been previously received from Mrs. James K. Pollock (donor no. 1937 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Humane Society of Huron Valley was founded in 1897. It was originally called the Humane Society of the City of Ann Arbor. Its name was later changed to the Washtenaw County Humane Society and then to its current name.
The record group includes minutes of meetings of the board, annual reports, and other subject files relating to animal control and the sheltering of various animals, and to the construction and expansion of the shelter.
Subjects:
Animal welfare.; Humane Society of Huron Valley.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Animal treatment.; Animals.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings.; Buildings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Humane Society of Huron Valley.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organizational records
  - Historical material (including mortgage material) (Box 1)
  - By-laws and articles of incorporation (Box 1)
  - Minute book, 1896-1941 (Box 1)
  - Loose items from minute book (Box 1)
  - Secretary's records (include minutes and annual reports)
    - 1941-1943 (Box 1)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 1)
    - 1954-1956 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
    - 1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports
    - 1948-1955/56 (Box 1)
    - 1956/57-1970 (Box 1)
  - New shelter file, 1949-1952, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Dog control file, 1947-1970, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Building plaque files
    - 1953 (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
  - Local animal ordinances (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Photographs of activities, staff, facilities and animals, 2 envelopes (Box 1)